<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Science And Technology Council</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Science And Technology Council</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 23:20:38 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Finance &amp; Analytics Club</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/blog-post-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 11:10:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/blog-post-1/</guid>
      <description>Our club aims to spread financial literacy amongst the campus community &amp;amp; aspires to make everyone adept in handling Personal Finances. We work at the merger of finance and analytics applying analytical understandings and tools in the areas of finance and economics. In the era of digitalization, rapid growth opportunities in fintech industries have sprung.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aerial Robotics </title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/teams-post-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 11:10:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/teams-post-1/</guid>
      <description>Currently, we are developing a fleet of autonomous aerial vehicles which can which can perform various tasks with state-of-the-art controls and algorithms at its core. Our current focus is on navigation, localization &amp;amp; mapping . Since navigating in indoor areas with accuracy can’t only be relied on GPS, So robot is getting its odometry data by multi-sensor-fusion using GPS, IMU and Visual methods.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AUV </title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/teams-post-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 11:10:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/teams-post-6/</guid>
      <description>Concern for man and his fate must always form the chief interest of all technical endeavors. Never forget this in the midst of your diagrams and equations. - Einstein One of the most eminent teams of IITK, Team AUV aims at developing an autonomous underwater vehicle capable of performing a set of tasks underwater from marker dropping, buoy detection to torpedo firing to surveillance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brain &amp; Cognitive Scoiety</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/news-post-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 11:10:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/news-post-1/</guid>
      <description>The Brain &amp;amp; Cognitive Society (BCS@IITK) is a student society at IIT Kanpur. We aim at studying Brain Science to reverse engineer human intelligence to create more general and intelligent AI&amp;rsquo;s for the future world. To achieve this we try to probe it from both ways developing better computational models of human cognition and relating the individual functionality of artificial computational models with that of humans.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Equipe de Robotique Autonome</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/teams-post-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 11:10:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/teams-post-5/</guid>
      <description>We are a team of undergraduates actively working with faculty and are dedicated to developing solutions to challenges in autonomous robotics and related domains. We develop cutting-edge robots aided by research and represent our university and nation in international competitions that see participants from prestigious colleges worldwide.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IITK Motorsports </title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/teams-post-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 11:10:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/teams-post-3/</guid>
      <description>IITK Motorsports has a vision - “Design &amp;amp; Build a Race Car”. We have four divisions, formula style racing car, all terrain vehicles, electric vehicles, efficient vehicles, with the last two being formed for the very first time this year. The first formula racing car we built, participated and performed decently in Formula Student Italy in September 2013.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Team Humanoid </title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/teams-post-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 11:10:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/teams-post-4/</guid>
      <description>When we think of robots, the first thing that we imagine is a picture of “C3PO” or “Chitti”, both exemplar symbols of the pop culture and more importantly, astonishingly awesome Humanoids! We at Team Humanoid are a group of enthusiastic students who are working towards developing a fully functional Humanoid robot of our own.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Team Vision </title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/teams-post-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 11:10:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/teams-post-2/</guid>
      <description>IGVC is one of the biggest international competition of Intelligent Ground Vehicles. In our very first participation, we secured the 5th position in Design Category of IGVC 2018. Each year, some of the most brilliant, hard working, and sincere people of any institute interested in Autonomy, team up to build vehicles to participate in the competition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DesCon Society</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/news-post-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 11:10:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/news-post-2/</guid>
      <description>The Design and Construction group organizes different activities including designing of popsicle bridge, Spaghetti Bridge and other types of bridges. Along with that different structural analysis are performed practically. Students are encouraged to perform activities on their own ideas and use of different softwares for structural analysis. Basics of designing and softwares are taught through lectures and workshops throughout the year.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IITK Consulting Group</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/news-post-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 11:10:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/news-post-4/</guid>
      <description>We engage in projects of giving expert advice to organisations working in a professional or technical field based on some data or information about the problem given to us by them. We have done several projects for various organisations and have been successful at them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Science Coffee House</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/news-post-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 11:10:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/news-post-5/</guid>
      <description>Science Coffee House is a warmly knit society of science enthusiasts. Taking roots from discussing anything and everything over a cup of coffee, the group has diversified into more activities. We organize the most interesting talks on all branches of science from Physics to Philosophy, host reading groups where you can explore novel and niche topics with your friends, and offer projects with definite goals in mind.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aeromodelling Club</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/blog-post-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 11:10:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/blog-post-2/</guid>
      <description>Aeromodelling Club, IIT Kanpur has been innovating new concept planes since 2006 and ever since then there was no turning back, with time the projects have improved, new conceptual airplanes have been made here and it has set its own benchmark at the world level (especially at SAE Aero). Summer project provides the first step to students to convert their innovations, their new ideas and their imaginations into reality, a working model. Similar work has been done this year, many new planes have been made and tested effectively..</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Astronomy Club</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/blog-post-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 11:10:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/blog-post-3/</guid>
      <description>The astronomy club attempts to bring about an interest and awareness in the field of Astronomy and Space Research. We intend to promote amateur astronomy through talks, competitions and shows. Astronomy is fun, but it gets better when you are a part of it as a community. Through various observation sessions by telescope at The Observatory for Astronomical Research (OAAR), we impart hands on skills and knowledge to all those willing to learn.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronics Club</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/blog-post-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 11:10:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/blog-post-4/</guid>
      <description>Electronics Club, earlier started as a hobby group has now expanded into a students’ organisation with the objective of inculcating a spirit of developing innovative, cutting edge technology solutions to real life problems. We provide a platform to the students’ body where any individual with an idea can approach the club freely to grasp the necessary technical skills required to turn that idea into a reality.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Game Development Society</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/news-post-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 11:10:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/news-post-3/</guid>
      <description>The Game Development Society aims to bring together people interested in making video games. We do this through small projects throughout the year, game jams, workshops and lectures. Video games are extremely diverse these days and everyone can play a part in the making of one. Whatever your interests may be, you&amp;rsquo;ll find a place for it here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Programming Club</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/blog-post-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 11:10:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/blog-post-5/</guid>
      <description>Programming is an art required in almost all spheres of life, and we inculcate that talent in the people who want to learn it. Introductory lectures and workshops cater to the people who are willing to learn coding. On the other hand, highly motivated and knowledgeable people are provided with necessary equipment/resources for their project. We organize activities ranging from App Development, Hacking to Algorithm development and Gaming.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robotics Club</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/blog-post-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 11:10:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/blog-post-6/</guid>
      <description>If you have ever even secretly aspired to build your own robot, then the Robotics Club, IITK is the place for you! We are a diverse group of over-enthused robotics nerds who find roots across all academic departments of the institute as well as ‘seniority’. The club is a student body which finds its place under the Science and Technology Council, Student Gymkhana, IIT Kanpur.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speedcubing Club</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/blog-post-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 11:10:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/blog-post-7/</guid>
      <description>We popularize speedcubing as a sport on campus by introducing other puzzles like Pyraminx, megaminx, skewb, square1, etc. Here, learning the 3x3x3 cube is just the beginning and a plethora of puzzles awaits you. You will get aware about various workshops being organised throughout the year about learning more and more about cubing. So if you ever wanted to learn about cubing or are really good at it, do come to our workshops.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
