<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Science And Technology Council</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Science And Technology Council</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 15:26:18 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AUV </title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/teams/teams-post-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 11:10:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/teams/teams-post-6/</guid>
      <description>Concern for man and his fate must always form the chief interest of all technical endeavors. Never forget this in the midst of your diagrams and equations. - Einstein One of the most eminent teams of IITK, Team AUV aims at developing an autonomous underwater vehicle capable of performing a set of tasks underwater from marker dropping, buoy detection to torpedo firing to surveillance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Equipe de Robotique Autonome</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/teams/teams-post-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 11:10:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/teams/teams-post-5/</guid>
      <description>We are a team of undergraduates actively working with faculty and are dedicated to developing solutions to challenges in autonomous robotics and related domains. We develop cutting-edge robots aided by research and represent our university and nation in international competitions that see participants from prestigious colleges worldwide.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IITK Motorsports </title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/teams/teams-post-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 11:10:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/teams/teams-post-3/</guid>
      <description>IITK Motorsports has a vision - “Design &amp;amp; Build a Race Car”. We have four divisions, formula style racing car, all terrain vehicles, electric vehicles, efficient vehicles, with the last two being formed for the very first time this year. The first formula racing car we built, participated and performed decently in Formula Student Italy in September 2013.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Team Humanoid </title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/teams/teams-post-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 11:10:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/teams/teams-post-4/</guid>
      <description>When we think of robots, the first thing that we imagine is a picture of “C3PO” or “Chitti”, both exemplar symbols of the pop culture and more importantly, astonishingly awesome Humanoids! We at Team Humanoid are a group of enthusiastic students who are working towards developing a fully functional Humanoid robot of our own.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Team Vision </title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/teams/teams-post-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 11:10:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/teams/teams-post-2/</guid>
      <description>IGVC is one of the biggest international competition of Intelligent Ground Vehicles. In our very first participation, we secured the 5th position in Design Category of IGVC 2018. Each year, some of the most brilliant, hard working, and sincere people of any institute interested in Autonomy, team up to build vehicles to participate in the competition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DesCon Society</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/societies/news-post-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 11:10:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/societies/news-post-2/</guid>
      <description>The Design and Construction group organizes different activities including designing of popsicle bridge, Spaghetti Bridge and other types of bridges. Along with that different structural analysis are performed practically. Students are encouraged to perform activities on their own ideas and use of different softwares for structural analysis. Basics of designing and softwares are taught through lectures and workshops throughout the year.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Science Coffee House</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/societies/news-post-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 11:10:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/societies/news-post-5/</guid>
      <description>Science Coffee House is a warmly knit society of science enthusiasts. Taking roots from discussing anything and everything over a cup of coffee, the group has diversified into more activities. We organize the most interesting talks on all branches of science from Physics to Philosophy, host reading groups where you can explore novel and niche topics with your friends, and offer projects with definite goals in mind.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Us</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 11:10:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>Discover the world of technology where you can innovate, learn, and create. Join us to explore new ideas, develop cutting-edge solutions, and advance your skills in a dynamic environment. Be part of the next breakthrough in technology—start your journey with us today!&#xA;What is the council about? Inspired by the principle that “Imagination is more important than knowledge,” the Science and Technology Council encourages individuals to transcend conventional limits. We provide a supportive platform where imagination can thrive and talents can be showcased.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 03:10:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/contact/</guid>
      <description>&#xD;Got a technical issue? Want to send feedback about a beta feature? Need details about our Business plan? Let us know.&#xA;Your Email:&#xD;Subject:&#xD;Your message:&#xD;Send Message&#xD;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/inter-iit/inter-iit-post-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/inter-iit/inter-iit-post-1/</guid>
      <description>&#xD;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/summer-projects/summer-projects-post-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/summer-projects/summer-projects-post-1/</guid>
      <description>&#xD;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/takneek/takneek-post-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/takneek/takneek-post-1/</guid>
      <description>&#xD;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aeromodelling Club</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/clubs/aeromodellingclub/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/clubs/aeromodellingclub/</guid>
      <description>Aeromodelling Club, IIT Kanpur has been innovating new concept planes since 2003 and ever since then there was no turning back, with time the projects have improved, new conceptual airplanes have been made here and it has set its own benchmark at the world level (especially at SAE Aero). Summer project provides the first step to students to convert their innovations, their new ideas and their imaginations into reality, a working model. Similar work has been done this year, many new planes have been made and tested effectively..</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brain and Cognitive Science Club</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/clubs/bcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/clubs/bcs/</guid>
      <description>Throughout the semester, the Brain and Cognitive Science Club  hosts various activities to engage members in the latest developments in the field. These include monthly Journal Club meetings, where students present and discuss recent research, fostering curiosity and knowledge sharing. The club also promotes three types of semester projects mainly replication of previous studies to verify their reproducibility, exploration of new research ideas, and projects aimed at learning for beginners. Additionally, BCS organizes talks and lectures by experts, along with workshops to provide foundational knowledge to newcomers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronics Club</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/clubs/electronicsclub/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/clubs/electronicsclub/</guid>
      <description>Electronics Club, is a students’ organisation passionate about electronics and technology, coming together to explore, learn, and innovate. Our club provides a collaborative environment where members can work on exciting projects, enhance their skills, and connect with like-minded individuals. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a beginner or an experienced enthusiast, you&amp;rsquo;ll find opportunities to engage in hands-on activities, attend workshops, and participate in competitions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finance and Analytics Club</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/clubs/financeandanalytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/clubs/financeandanalytics/</guid>
      <description>Finace and Analytics Club , IIT Kanpur ever since its formation in 2020 ,has been aiming to prepare IITK for corporate &amp;amp; research-based financial problems grounded in quantitative &amp;amp; visualization methods..</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gallery</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gallery/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Game Development Club</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/clubs/gamedev/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/clubs/gamedev/</guid>
      <description>The Game Development Club at IIT Kanpur is a vibrant community of game development enthusiasts. The club actively participates in national and international game jams, encouraging creativity and innovation. It organizes summer and winter projects, along with bootcamps tailored to introduce freshers to the world of game development. Additionally, the club represents IIT Kanpur in the prestigious Inter-IIT Tech Meet, showcasing its members&amp;rsquo; skills and passion for game development. Whether seasoned developers or beginners, members find a supportive environment to learn, create, and collaborate on exciting game development projects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IITK Consulting Group</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/societies/icg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/societies/icg/</guid>
      <description>We are a group of consulting and data science enthusiasts at the IIT Kanpur Consulting Group, established in 2018. Our vision is to harness data science and strategy consulting skills to help organizations extract valuable insights from their data and devise growth strategies for them, ultimately driving positive social impact. By bringing together a talented pool of individuals, we ensure that we provide outstanding solutions to address the pressing societal challenges at hand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Programming Club</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/clubs/programmingclub/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/clubs/programmingclub/</guid>
      <description>Programming Club is a community of IITK students who are highly enthusiastic about development, algorithms, security, ML, and all other aspects of programming.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robotics Club</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/clubs/roboticsclub/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/clubs/roboticsclub/</guid>
      <description>The Robotics Club at IIT Kanpur, part of the Science and Technology Council, is a diverse group of students passionate about robotics. They work on projects that involve designing, building, and programming robots for academic research, competitions, and personal interest. The club covers various technical aspects of robotics, including mechanical design, electronics, and coding. They provide workshops, tutorials, and one-on-one mentorship, offering access to tools, components, and a workspace. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a beginner or experienced, the club supports your journey into the technical world of robotics, helping you create robots like R2D2, Transformers, or WALL-E.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web_heads</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/web_division/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/web_division/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
